Guide to the Radical and Labor Songbook Collection, circa 1850s-1980s.
Radical and Labor Songbook Collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Radical and Labor Songbook Collection, circa 1850s-1980s.
8611
Ronald D., Cohen, 1940-
5.5 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
This collection is comprised of radical song books, music sheets, periodical issues and broadsides spanning the period ca. 1850 to 1990, with primary emphasis on the period 1900-1940. It includes rare pieces (such as numerous early editions of the I.W.W. "Little Red Songbook") as well as ephemeral song-sheets and song-books. Periodicals represented in the collection include "Sing Out!", "Broadside: the Topical Song Magazine", and "Promenade," an influential leftist folk-dance mimeo. The collection is overwhelmingly comprised of American imprints (including several foreign-language works printed in America), but also includes some presentative British publications. The core of the collection was put together by musicologist Ronald D. Cohen, and formed the basis for his monograph, Work and Sing: A History of Occupational and Labor Union Songs in the United States (Oakland: 2010). Approximately 200 more items were added to this core to create the current collection.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection is comprised of radical song books, music sheets, periodical issues and broadsides spanning the period ca. 1850 to 1990, with primary emphasis on the period 1900-1940. It includes rare pieces (such as numerous early editions of the I.W.W. "Little Red Songbook") as well as ephemeral song-sheets and song-books. Periodicals represented in the collection include "Sing Out!", "Broadside: the Topical Song Magazine", and "Promenade," an influential leftist folk-dance mimeo. The collection is overwhelmingly comprised of American imprints (including several foreign-language works printed in America), but also includes some presentative British publications. The core of the collection was put together by musicologist Ronald D. Cohen, and formed the basis for his monograph, Work and Sing: A History of Occupational and Labor Union Songs in the United States (Oakland: 2010). Approximately 200 more items were added to this core to create the current collection.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cohen, Ronald D., 1940-
Subjects:
Folk music -- Political aspects -- United States.; Folk music -- Great Britian.; Folk music -- United States.; Labor movement -- United States.; Music.; Popular music -- United States.; Songs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Individual song books, music sheets, periodical issues and broadsides
Series II. Songbooks series
CONTAINER LIST
- Individual song books, music sheets, periodical issues and broadsides, 1897-2013
  Arranged alphabetically
  - Anonymous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Untitled songbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Author unknown
  - A, 1932-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sing America, Undated; Allan, Anne; Workers Bookshop (Box 1, Folder 2)
      New York, New York
    - Abraham Lincoln Lives Again, 1938; Allan, Lewis; Bob Miller (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Songs of the Almanac Singers Book 1, 1942; Almanac Singers; Bob Miller (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - March and Sing!, 1937; American Music League (Box 1, Folder 2)
      First edition.
    - A Book of Songs for Picket Lines, Meetings, Parties, and Other Union Occasions, 1940; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Book of Songs for Picket Lines, Meetings, Parties, and Other Union Occasions, 1940; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Songs of Struggle and Memo, 1932; Arise Publishing Co (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Song Book, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B, 1897-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Democratic March, 1956; Baker, Herbert; Green, Johny; Herbert Baker and Johnny Green (Box 1, Folder 3)
      First edition
    - Cavalry Patrol (Song of the Steppes), 1944; Bantock, Granville; Bantock, Helen; W. Paxton and Co. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      London, United Kingdom
    - Guerillas and Heroes (From Border to Border), 1944; Bantock, Granville; Bantock, Helen; W. Paxton and Co. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Maine Stands United; Rieve and His Administration, 1952: Convention Songs, 1952; Bryant Press; Biddeford-Saco Joint Board; Central Maine Joint Board; Lewiston Joint Board (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Portland, Maine
    - Nine Boys and Girls in Arkansas, 1970-1979; Bilbew, A.C. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Dedicated to the courage and dignity of their parents. Song: Lets [sic] Go for Civil Rights. First edition
      Los Angeles, California
    - Boxcar Sing Along, 2013; Black Butte Center for Railroad Culture (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Weed, California
    - The Hand with the Hammer, 1897; Burrowes Peter E.; Brounoff, Platon; National Executive Committee, Socialist Labor Party (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C (1), 1938-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - War No More, 1966; Carichner, Roberta Slavit; Providence Peace Action Committee (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Providence, Rhode Island
    - Cancion Protesta No. 1, 1968; Centro de la Cancin Protesta (Box 1, Folder 4)
      All Published
      Habana, Cuba
    - Sing for Victory, 1942; Chase, Murray; Murray Chase (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - May First Celebration 1939, 1939; Chicago Joint Board Cloak and Dressmakers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Chicago, Illinois
    - The Gol-Dern Red, 1947; Claiborne, Bob; People's Songs (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Reprint
    - It's My Union, 1947; Claiborne, Bob; People's Songs (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Commonwealth Labor Songs: A Collection of Old and New Songs for the Use of Labor Unions, 1938; Commonwealth College (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Mena, Arkansas
  - C (2), 1907-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - AFL / CIO CWA Song Book, 1960-1969; Communications Workers of America (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Washington, DC
    - Lenin Memorial Meeting, 1939; Communist Party (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    - Songs of the Revolution, 1920-1929; Communist Party of Great Britain (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Second edition
    - Transit Tunes for 1941, 1941; Congress of Industrial Organizations (C.I.O.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sit-In Songs, 1962; Congress of Racial Equality (Box 1, Folder 5)
      [New york?] First edition
    - We Shall Overcome, 1966; Suzuki, Lewis; Congress of Racial Equality (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Campaign Songs, 1907; Cooperative Printing Co (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Work and Sing: An International Songbook, 1950-1959; Cooperative Recreation Service (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Third edition
      Delaware, Ohio
  - C Oversized, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Song of Separation, 1920; Chaplin, Ralph; Liebich, R.I.; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - D (1), 1934-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Daily Worker Banquet Nov. 26, 1934, 1934; Daily Worker (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Mass Singing will be diredcted by Alex Solomon of the Pierre Degeyter Club. Mimeographed Broadside
    - Songs to Stop Seabrook by; A Collection of Anti-Nuke Songs, 1978; Dellavalle, Beth; DiGiuseppe, David; Van Pelt, Jenny; Clamshell Alliance (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Portsmouth, New Hampshire
    - Movement Songbook: Songs of Socialism, Labor, Women, Civil Rights, Peace, 1975; Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D (2), 1933-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Workers Party Song Book, 1960-1969; Democratic Workers Party (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Rhapsodies in Red: Songs for the Social Revolution, 1933; De Witt, S.A.; Rand School Press (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Wrapper Issue
    - Rhapsodies in Red: Songs for the Social Revolution, 1933; De Witt, S.A.; Rand School Press (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Cloth Issue
  - E (1), 1938-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Friction in the System: A New Songbook of Political Music, 1976; Eastbay People's Music (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Berkeley, California
    - Songbook; Canciones, 1990-1999; Education Department, Texas AFL-CIO (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Austin, Texas
    - Let's Sing!, 1942; Educational Department - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Celebrating the Opening of the Fall Term, 1938; Educational Department - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Everybody Sings, 1942; Educational Department - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - E (2), 1978-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chantons Nos Luttes! Sing of Our Struggles! Sing of Revolution!, 1978; En Lutte! (In Struggle!) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Montral, Canada
    - The Earth First! Songbook, 1993; Earth First! (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Missoula, Montana
  - F (1), 1910-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Immortal Negro Melodies: These Are Songs Paul Robeson Sings, 1937; Family Journal (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Yesterday Is Hardly Gone, 1975; Farrell, Russ (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Inscribed and Signed
      Portland, Oregon
    - Ontario Youth Festival for a Greater Canada Song Book, 1954; Festival Co-Ordinating Committee (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. but 1954
      Ontario, Canada
    - Uusi Tyven Laulukirja, 1910; Tymiehen Kustannusyhti (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Finnish Language Labor Songbook. First edition
      Hancockissa, Michigan
  - F (2), 1895-2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Constitution: American Square Dance Group 4/5/39, 2000-2009; Folklore Centrum (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Stockholm, Sweden
    - Rebel Song Book. Eighty-Seven Socialist and Labor Songs for Voice and Piano, 1935; Friedman, Samuel H.; Bachman, Dorothy; Rand School Press (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Workers Songs, 1930-1939; Friends of the Soviet Union (Box 2, Folder 2)
      San Francisco, California
    - Himno de Riego: National Anthem of the Spanish Republic, 1937; Friends of the Spanish Republic (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ein Knigliches Mahl, 1895; Fuchs, Eduard; Druck und Verlag von M. Ernst (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Mnchen
  - G, 1937-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Me and My Captain; Chain Gang; Negro Songs of Protest, 1939; Gellert, Lawrence; Adomian, Lan; Hours Press (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ding Dong Dollar: Anti-Polaris Songs, 1961; Glasgow Song Guild (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Fifth (Eskimo) edition
      Glasgow, Scotland
    - No Pasaran! They Shall Not Pass!, 1937; Gonzalez, Leopoldo and Henry Jordan; American Music League (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Dedicated to the Heroic Loyalist Soldiers who in Spain are Defending World Democracy
  - H (1), 1948-1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Songs of Joe Hill, 1955; Hill, Joe; People's Artists Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Barrie Stavis and Frank Harmon, eds.
    - Singer, Joe Hill (Joe Hillstrom), 1926; Hill, Joe; People's Artists Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Includes songs by others honoring Joe Hill. In Swedish
    - The People's Song Book, 1956; Hille, Waldemar; People's Artists Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The People's Song Book, 1948; Hille, Waldemar; Oak Publications (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Forward by Alan Lomax; B.A. Botkin, pref. 6th (1962) printing
  - H (2), 1939-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Songs of "Faith in Man" for Religious Liberals, 1960; Hille, Waldemar; Hodgin Press; First Unitarian Church of Los Angeles (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Labor Songs, 1939; Horton, Zilphia; Textile Workers Union of America (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - H Oversized, 1915-1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Rebel Girl, 1915; Hill, Joe; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - American's Young Black Joe, 1942; Hughes, Langston; Carpenter, Elliot; Hughes and Carpenter (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - I, 1940-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Hoadl'y Songbook, being mostly a singable polemic, 1963; Indiana University - Youth Socialist Alliance; Der Untergrund Verlag (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Bloomington, Indiana
    - Songs for Victory, Undated; I.W.O. Lodge 551 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Let's Sing, 1940-1949; Industrial Department (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - IWW (1), 1914-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Songs of the Workers on the Road in the Jungles and in the Shops, 1914; Industrial Workers of the World Publishing Bureau (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Eighth (Joe Hill) edition
      Cleveland, Ohio
    - Songs of the Workers on the Road in the Jungles and in the Shops, 1918; Industrial Workers of the World Publishing Bureau (Box 2, Folder 7)
      14th edition
    - Songs of the Workers: Issued July, 1956, in commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the I.W.W., 1956; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 2, Folder 7)
      29th edition
    - I.W.W Songs, 1923; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 2, Folder 7)
      18th edition
    - I.W.W. Songs, 1925; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 2, Folder 7)
      20th edition
    - I.W.W. Songs, 1932; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 2, Folder 7)
      24th edition
    - I.W.W. Songs to fan the flames of discontent, 2007; Industrial Workers of the World; Charles H. Kerr Publishing Company (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Reprint of the Nineteenth edition (1923)
  - IWW (2), 1920-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Canadian Wobbly Songbook is dedicated to all musicians who lend their skills to the picket line, 1990; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Toronto, Canada
    - IWW Labor Arts Presents Songs of the Wobblies Sung by Joe Glazer and Bill Friedland, 1953; Industrial Workers of the World Labor Arts (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Detroit, Michigan
    - Internatsional'nyi Sbornik Revoliutsionnykh i Rabochikh Pesen i Stikhotvorenii [Russian Song Book], 1920; Izdanie Ispolintel'nogo Komiteta Russkikh Otdelov Soiuza I.R.M (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Text in Russian
      Chikago, Illinois
    - (I.W.W.)Songs for Peace 1986, 1986; Lakeside Press (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Madison, Wisconsin
  - J, 1937-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mayday Sing-Along, 1995; Jamaica Jo Mamas; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Songs for Peace, 1940; Jefferson, Bill (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Free-Spain Fiesta Cabaret, 1937; Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - J Oversized, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - I Love You, 1920; Jones, Bill; Soley, Edwin C.; Bill Jones (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - K (1), 1900-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - People's Songs, Vol. 1, no. 3, April, 1946, 1946; Kent, Paul; Scott, Michael; Seeger, Pete; Hays, Lee; People's Songs (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Songs, 1900; Kerr, Charles H.; Charles H. Kerr and Company Co-Operative (Box 3, Folder 2)
      First Thus
    - Socialist Songs with Music, 1902; Kerr, Charles H.; Charles H. Kerr and Company Co-Operative (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Songs with Music, 1902; Kerr, Charles H.; Charles H. Kerr and Company (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Fourth edition, Revised and Enlarged
    - The Little Read Songbook, 1999; King, Charlie.; Vaguely Reminiscent Sounds (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Assembled by Ted Warmbrand and Karen Brandow. First edition. Inscribed and Signed by King.
      Hamden, Connecticut
  - K (2), 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1956 Buck's Rock Folk Song Book, 1956; Kornfeld, Barry (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - A Ballad of August Bondi, 1955; Kramer, Aaron (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Offprint
    - The Hanging (Ballad) from "Denmark Vesey", Undated; Kramer, Aaron; Hille, W. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Johnny Sagebrush's Li'l Green Songbook, 1981; Koehler, Bart; Earth First! (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Rio Ranch, New Mexico
    - Listen to the Mockingbird: Satiric Songs to Tunes You Know, 1973; Kupferberg, Tuli; Mockingbird Press (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - K Oversized, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Hooray for the C.C.C., 1934; Kilgore, Clive H.; G.B. Harris (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Inscribed and Signed by G.B. Harris
      Erie, Pennsylvania
  - L (1), 1936-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Lonesome Train: A Cantata (A Musical Legend), 1945; Lampell, Millard; Robinson, Earl; Sun Music Co (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Miner Sings: A Collection of Folk-Songs and Ballads of the American Anthracite Miner, 1936; LeMon, Melvin;; J. Fischer and Bro. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Introduction by George Korson
    - Welcome! You have the vocal chords -- Here are the Lyrics -- Let's All Sing, 1946; Levine, George; AYD Clubs? (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cantos de la Nueva Resistencia Espaola, 1939-1961, 1963; Liberovici, Sergio; Straniero, Michele L.; Editorial El Siglo Ilustrado (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Montevideo, Uruguay
  - L (2), 1912-2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Songbook Vol. 1: Radical Songs, 1950-1959; Libertarian League (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The International, 1970-1979; Lieblich, Rudolf; Kerr, Charles H.; Industrial Workers of the World (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Best Antiwar Song Ever Written, 2012; Lighter, Jonathan; CAMSCO Music (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Windsor, New Jersey
    - Coaldust Ballads, 1952; Lloyd, A.L.; Workers' Music Association Ltd. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Some Songs of Socialism, 1912; Local Rochester, Socialist Party (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Rochester, New Yotk
  - M (1), 1954-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Socialist Songs, 1961; Mathews, Race; Victorian Fabian Society (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Melbourne, Austrailia
    - Camo Carols, 1989; McCall, Julie; Konopacki, Mike; Labor Heritage Foundation (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Little Black Songbook, 1960; McElderry, Rod; Little Sandy Review Press (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Shuttle and Cage: Industrial Folk-Ballads, 1954; MacColl, Ewan; Hargail Music Press (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Proletfolk: A Dialectical Compilation of United Front and Sectarian Songs, Undated; Meisenbach, Steve; Miller, Jim (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Joy to UC: Free Speech Carols, 1964; SR-25861; Miller, Dustin Mark (Box 3, Folder 6)
      7" reocord with separate lyric sheet.
      Oakland, California
  - M (2), 1907-1911 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Songs of Socialism for Local Branch and Campaign Work, Public Meetings, Labor, Fraternal, and Religious Organizations, Social Gatherings, and the Home, 1907; Moyer, Harvey P.; Brotherhood Publishing, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Songs of Socialism for local branch and campaign work, public meetings, labor, fraternal, and religious organizations, social gatherings, and the home, 1911; Moyer, Harvey P.; Co-Operative Printing Company (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Sixth edition. With Prospectus.
  - M Overzied, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The March of Union Labor: Two Step, 1901; Maloney, James C.; James C. Maloney (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - N, 1930-1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - National Farmer's Union Annual Convention: "Going to Town!" November 19-20, 1935, Armory, Kankakee, Illinois, 1935; National Farmers' Union (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Kankakee, Illinois
    - Songs for Seamen, 1947; National Maritime Union; CIO (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Spirit of the People, 1970-1979; New American Movement (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Musician's edition
      Minneapolis, Minnesota
    - The Spirit of the People, 1970-1979; New American Movement (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Likely the Singer's edition
    - Songs of Struggle: 50 Songs, 1930-1939; New York Workers' Bookshop and Circulating Library (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Women's Rally, 1969; November Action Coalition (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - P (1), 1937-1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Knowledge is Power, Undated; Paparello, L.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Folk Songs for Conservatives, 1964; Parmentel, Noel E., Jr.; Dodge, Marshall J., III; Unicorn Press (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Song of the Red Cavalry (Budenny's March), Undated; Paul, E.; Paul, C.; The Daily Worker (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Centralia Horror Up and In Action, 1927; Petersen, Henry C.; Washington Branch General Defense Committee (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Seattle, Washington
  - P (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Let There Be Music / Song: The Song Book of the Singing People's Alliance, 1970-1979; People's Alliance for a Cooperative Commonwealth (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Chapel Hill, North Carolina
    - "Spring Fever" Hootenanny and Dance, Undated; People's Artists (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Spring Fever" Hootenanny, Undated; People's Artists (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sing Out! Vol. 1 No. 1, 1950; People's Artists (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Peoples Sing: 100 International Ghetto, Resistance, Nebraskagro, Labor, Folk, Youth Songs, 1950; Peoples Sing (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Americana: A joint concert of Earl Robinson and the People's Songs Chorus under the direction of Sonny Vale, 1948; People's Songs (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Flipside notes dated 1959
    - Hootenanny, 1946; People's Songs of California (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - People's Songs Wordbook No. 1, 1947; People's Songs (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - P (3), 1913-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Nuovissimo Canzoniere Sociale Musicato, 1913; Perrini, P.; P. Perrini (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Workmen's Circle Hymn, 1929; Posner, Meyer; Metro Music Co (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Let's Sing!, 1940-1949; Proletarian Notes (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - It Could Be a Wonderful World: Songs of Peace and Freedom, 1965; Putnam, Jean (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Yellow Springs, Ohio
  - P Oversized, 1905-1933 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Jolly Blacksmiths March Two-Step, 1905; Paull, E.T. Braham, E.; E.T. Paull Music Co. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - NRA Song, 1933; Phillips, Abdiel; Davies, Bessie (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Plymouth, Pennsylvania
  - R, 1938-1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Sing While You Fight, 1942; Recreation Department, United Wholesale and Warehouse Employees Local 65, U.R.W.E.A., C.I.O. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Songs for Labor, Undated; Research and Education Dept.; Oil Workers Intl. Union - -C.I.O. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Little Boxes and other handmade songs, 1964; Reynolds, Malvina; Oak Publications (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Second Printing
    - Six Songs for Democracy, 1940-1949; Robeson, Paul; Music Room (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - America Sings, 1939; Robinson, Earl; Workers Bookshop (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Earl Robinson and Will Geer present a Cavalcade of American Song, 1941; Robinson, Earl and Will Geer; Committee to Aid Agricultural Workers (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - One Big Union for Two, 1939; Rome, Harold; Mills Music Publishers (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Nobody Makes a Pass At Me, 1938; Rome, Harold J.; Mills Music Inc. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - F.D.R. Jones, 1938; Rome, Harold J.; Chappell and Co (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New Pins and Needles, Undated; Rome, Harold; Schrank, Joseph; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - R Oversized, 1918-1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bolsheviki Glide: Song, 1918; Randall, Carl; Tierney, Harry; Jerome H. Remick and Co. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Refugee (Flichtling) with Yiddish, Spanish, and Chinese Words, 1939; Richter, William B.; Hays, Billy; Capano, Frank; Tin Pan Alley (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Inscribed and Signed by Capano
  - S (1), 1913-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Sandhog Song from the Folk-Opera "Sandhog" (Act II, Scene I), Undated; Salt and Robinson (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mit Gezang Tzum Kamf, 1932; Schaeffer, Jacob; International Workers Order (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - If You Love Your Uncle Sam (Bring Them Home), 1966; Seeger, Pete; Providence Peace Action Committee (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Some Songs for Socialist Singers, 1913; Shedd, Kendrick P. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Spanish Civil War - Songbooks: Brigadas Internacionales / Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1937 - 1967, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mechanics Song, Undated; Socialist Labor Party (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - I. The Internationale; II. The March of the Workers, Undated; Socialist Labor Party of America (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - S (2), 1942-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Socialist Youth League Song Book, Undated; Socialist Youth League (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Teacher's Blues, 1947; Stearns, Marshall; Seeger, Pete; People's Songs (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - America Sings for Victory, 1943; Stevens, Alexander; Workers Book Shop (Box 4, Folder 6)